As times change, difficult cases increase in number!
تتضاعف القضايا المعقّدة مع مضيّ خط الوقت
Today's case is about a face pack! Can makeup hide the evidence?!
قضيّة اليوم عن قناع وجه! أيمكن لمساحيق التجميل إخفاء الدليل؟
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Kojima-san! It's Beika Security!
!كوجيما-سان! نحن أمن بيكا
Is something wrong, Kojima-san?!
!أهناك خطبٌ ما، كوجيما-سان؟
Let's go!
!هيّا بنا
Right!
أجل
Kojima-san! We're opening the door!
!كوجيما-سان! سنفتح الباب
Do it!
افتحه
Right!
أجل
Huh?
ماذا؟
I'm sorry! Did I scare you?
آسفة، هل أخفتكما؟
No, no...
...كلا
I was putting my face pack on, so I couldn't answer right away.
كنتُ أضع قناع الوجه فلم أستطع الإجابة فوراً
Your security alarm went off... did something happen?
فُعّل جهاز إنذارك الأمني، أحصل أمرٌ ما؟
No, nothing at all.
كلا، لا شيء أبداً
Must've been a glitch...
لعلّه كان خللاً
Chiba-san...
تشيبا-سان
Looks like he's the culprit.
يبدو أنّه الفاعل
He must've crossed the infrared sensors.
لا بدّ أنّه عبر المستشعرات تحت الحمراء
They're so sensitive that this happens once in a while.
إنّها حسّاسة بحيث تقع أمور كهذه من فترة لفترة
Oh?
حقّاً؟
Well, please be sure to lock up!
احرصي على إقفال الباب من فضلك
Thanks for your help.
شكراً لقدومكم
Boy, am I full!
أكلتُ للتخمة
China has nothing on this place's Chinese cuisine! Don't you think?!
الصين نفسها لا تستطيع منافسة الطبخ الصينيّ لهذا المطعم، صحيح؟
Actually, ramen's pretty much the same anywhere...
الرامن نفسه أينما ذهبت في الواقع
Oh, it's already this late?
تأخّر الوقت لهذا الحدّ؟
Not good! Yoko-chan's drama show is on tonight!
!لا يصحّ! ستُعرض دراما يوكو-تشان الليلة
Yoko-chan! I'm coming home now!
!يوكو-تشان! أنا عائد للبيت الآن
Wait, Dad!
!لحظة، أبي
Dad!
!أبي
A-Are you all right?!
أ-أأنت بخير؟
Idiot! Watch where you're going!
!أحمق! احترس
Securities Employee Izumi Takeo (25)
...آ-آسف، كنت
Watch where you're driving, will you?!
!انتبه وأنت تقود
Isn't it also your fault for crossing the street without paying attention?
أليست غلطتك لعبور الشارع قبل النظر؟
Yeah!
صحيح
What's your guys' deal?
ما-ما مشكلتكما؟
Hello?
مرحباً
Yes. Megure-san?
أجل، ميغوري-سان؟
Eh?! Police Investigation Section ♪1?!
!ماذا؟ القسم 1 لتحقيقات الشرطة؟
Hello! Mori here!
!مرحباً! أنا موري
Why am I here? Oh, that doesn't matter!
لمَ أنا هنا؟ لا يهمّ ذلك
What case are you on?
ما القضية التي تعمل عليها؟
Eh?! He's involved with a murder case?!
ماذا؟ ذو صلة في جريمة قتل؟
Very well! You can count on me!
!فهمت! يمكنك الاعتماد عليّ
Wait, Mori--!
...لحظة، موري
Oh, no, you don't!
!لن تهرب
Give it up!
!استسلم
You just crossed paths with the peerless Mori Kogoro!
قادتك الأقدار ليديّ المتحرّي !الأعظم على الأرض، موري كوغورو-ساما
W-Wait! I have no idea what's going on!
!ا-انتظر! لا أدري ما الذي يجري أبداً
Don't play dumb! You can spout your excuses when we get there!
!لا تتظاهر بالجهل! يمكنك قول أعذارك عندما نصل
Would the police call a suspect on the phone?
هل تستدعي الشرطة مشتبهاً به عبر الهاتف؟
But he's...
...لكن، هذا الشخص
Inspector!
!حضرة المفتّش
C'mon!
تعال
Oh, thanks for coming.
شكراً لقدومك
I've brought the suspect, as requested!
!جلبتُ المشتبه به كما طلبت
Huh? What're you talking about?
ماذا؟ ما الذي تقوله؟
Think about it.
فكّر بالأمر
If Izumi Takeo-san were a suspect, we obviously wouldn't call him.
لو كان إيزومي تاكيو-سان مُشتبهاً به لما اتّصلنا به على الهاتف
Oh, now that you mention it...
...بذكرك للأمر
Yeah, I figured as much.
أجل، كما ظننت
TM Securities, Beika Branch.
شركة تي إم الأمنية، فرع بيكا
Izumi Takeo-san. You visited this home tonight, yes?
إيزومي تاكيو-سان، أتيت لهذا المنزل الليلة، صحيح؟
Uhh, no... Yes.
كـ-كلا... أقصد أجل
You came at 8:00 exactly, and left at 8:40. Correct?
أتيتَ هنا تمام الثامنة وغادرت عند الثامنة والأربعين، صحيح؟
I don't know the exact times...
لا أعرف الوقت بالضبط
How do you know the times so exactly?
كيف حددتم الوقت؟
He's on the security camera tape.
إنّه على شريط كاميرات المراقبة
Ah! So he did kill her, then?!
!ارتكب الجريمة إذاً؟
Nope.
كلا
After Izumi-san left... Yes, at 8:50, the daughter stopped by.
،بعد مغادرة إيزومي-سان... أجل أي عند الثامنة والخمسين، أتت الابنة
The victim was still alive then.
كانت الضحيّة لا تزال على قيد الحياة
What's more, security personnel saw her at 9:00.
كما أنّ أحد أفراد الأمن رآها عند التاسعة
Security personnel?
أفراد الأمن؟
A cat snuck into the yard and set off the security alarms.
تسلّل قطّ للفناء وأطلق إنذار الأمن
I contacted Izumi-san to learn more about the victim.
اتّصلتُ بإيزومي-سان لمعرفة المزيد عن الضحيّة
Oh, I see.
حسناً
Who is the victim, anyway?
من الضحيّة بأيّ حال؟
Kojima Ikuko. She managed a chain of discount electronics stores.
كوجيما إيكوكو، كانت تدير سلسلة متاجر إلكترونيات مخفّضة
She was strangled to death.
ماتت خنقاً
Well, now that everyone is here, let us begin.
لنبدأ مع وجود الجميع هنا
Mori-kun.
موري-كن
This is the victim's daughter, Chihiro-san.
هذه ابنة الضحيّة، تشيهيرو-سان
And the one who found her, Yoshioka-san.
ومن اكتشف الجثّة، يوشيوكا-سان
Who's he?
من هذا الرجل؟
The great detective, Mori Kogoro.
المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو
The Mori Kogoro?!
!موري كوغورو؟ ذاك المتحرّي الشهير؟
Now, then. According to the security video...
...حسناً، وفقاً لكاميرات المراقبة
Izumi-san arrived at 8:00, and left at 8:40.
وصل إيزومي-سان عند الثامنة، وغادر عند 8:40
Chihiro-san arrived at 8:50, and left at 9:10.
،وصلت تشيهيرو-سان عند 8:50 ثمّ غادرت عند 9:10
Then Yoshioka-san arrived at 9:20, and discovered the body,
،وأخيراً وصل يوشيوكا-سان عند 9:20 واكتشف الجثّة
and called the police at 9:31.
واتّصل بالشرطة عند 9:31
I assume this is all correct?
أتوقع أنّ لا مشاكل في هذا؟
If it's on tape, then of course it is.
إن كان على التسجيل فبالطبع
Her own mother just died! Why is she...
...قُتِلت أمّها للتوّ، لكنّها لا تُبدي
I take it your mother was still alive when you left?
أفترض أنّ أمّك كانت لا تزال على قيد الحياة عندما غادرتِ
Of course she was!
!بالطبع
Or, what? Are you suggesting I killed my mother?!
أو ماذا؟ تقصد أنّي قتلت أمّي؟
No, no, nothing of the sort...
...كلا، لم ألمّح لشيء كهذا
Basically, that puts the time of death between 9:10 and 9:20.
بشكلٍ عام، وقت الوفاة المرجّح هو بين 9:10 و 9:20
Was the house locked?
أكان المنزل مقفلاً؟
The front door was apparently open when Mr. Yoshioka arrived.
كان الباب الأمامي مفتوحاً عندما أتى السيّد يوشيوكا وفقما يبدو
All other doors were locked from the inside.
كانت بقيّة الأبواب مقفلة من الداخل
Meaning the killer was one of these three who used the front door!
ما يعني أنّ القاتل كان أحد هؤلاء الثلاثة الذين دخلوا من الباب الأمامي
Well, time-wise, we can probably discount Izumi-san.
حسناً، يمكننا استبعاد إيزومي-سان بالنظر للوقت
Hold on! He has a motive for killing my mother!
!انتظر! لديه دافع لقتل أمي
He was on the verge of being sued by her!
!كانت على وشك أن تقاضيه
He wasted 300 million of her money on a lousy investment!
أهدر 300 مليون من أموالها على استثمار فاشل
T-That was...
...كـ-كان ذلك
So it was you!
!كان أنت بالفعل إذاً
W-What?!
...كـ-كلا
I bet you pretended to leave, and snuck in when the coast was clear!
!تظاهرت بالمغادرة ثمّ تسللت والطريق مفتوح
I don't think he's the killer.
لا أظنّه القاتل
Conan-kun...
كونان-كن
If the time of death was between 9:10 and 9:20,
إذا كان وقت الوفاة المقدّر بين 9:10 و9:20
time-wise, Izumi-san couldn't have done it.
فيستحيل أن يكون القاتل إيزومي-سان
How's that?
ماذا؟
Don't you remember? It was around 9:40...
....ألا تذكر، عند التاسعة والأربعين
9:40...
التاسعة والأربعين؟
Oh, yeah!
!فهمت
What is it?
ماذا؟
Come to think of it, he was with us in Beika at 9:40...
صحيح، كان معنا في بيكا عند التاسعة والأربعين
I see. It'd take at least fifty to sixty minutes to get there by car...
فهمت، يستغرق الذهاب هناك خمسين إلى ستّين دقيقة بالسيّارة
I guess he's in the clear.
إنّه بريء بالفعل
But he could've done it somehow!
!لكن كان يمكنه فعلها بشكلٍ ما
The lady has a point!
!الآنسة محقّة
But, Miss. Didn't you have a reason of your own to kill her, too?
لكن يا آنسة، أليس لديك دافع بدورك؟ لقتل الرئيسة؟
Come again?!
!ماذا؟
What do you mean?
ما قصدك؟
Her mother severed all ties with her because of her fiance.
قطعت أمّها كلّ الروابط بها بسبب خطيبها في السابق
Apparently, her husband is behind bars...
...زوجها مسجون الآن وفقما يبدو
Mind your own business!
!لا تتدخل فيما لا يخصّك
And even if that were true, why would I need to kill my mother?!
ولو كان ذلك صحيحاً، لمَ قد أقتل أمّي؟
I heard you asked her for a loan, but were harshly brushed aside!
سمعتُ أنّك طلبتِ منها قرضاً، ورفضتك زجراً
And that that fueled a big family quarrel...
وأدّى ذلك لشجار عائليّ حاد
You're the one who argued with her and said you'd kill her someday!
أنت من تشاجر معها في العمل !وقلت أنّك ستقتلها يوماً
W-What nonsense!
!هـ-هراء
In any case, it would appear one of you two is the killer.
بأيّ حال، يبدو أنّ القاتل أحدكما
So, what brought you here tonight, Chihiro-san?
إذاً، ما الذي جلبك هنا الليلة يا تشيهيرو-سان؟
I was called here. To be lectured at.
استدعتني لتعظني
And that made you snap and kill her!
وفقدتِ السيطرة على أعصابك وقتلتِها
Will you get serious, you lousy detective?!
!يكفي هذا أيّها المتحرّي الفاشل
L-Lousy?!
!فـ-فاشل؟
Now, now, Mori-kun!
!على رسلك يا موري-كن
And what brought you here, Yoshioka-san?
إذاً، ما الذي جلبك هنا يا يوشيوكا-سان؟
A work-related meeting.
لقاء عمل
The circumstances definitely indicate it was one of these two...
تشير الظروف لكون القاتل أحدهما بالفعل
Here's the tape. Let me know if you remember or notice anything.
سنطلب منكم مشاهدة تسجيل كاميرات المراقبة من باب الحيطة، أخبرونا إذا ما لاحظتم شيئاً
First, Izumi-san arrives at 8:00 on the dot and goes inside.
وصل إيزومي-سان بدايةً عند تمام الثامنة ودخل
And it's at 8:40 exactly that he leaves.
ثمّ غادر عند 8:40
Next is Chihiro-san. The time is 8:50.
التالية تشيهيرو-سان، الوقت هو 8:50
Then, ten minutes later, Ms. Ikuko steps out to speak with the guards.
ثمّ بعد 10 دقائق، خرجت السيّدة إيكوكو للكلام مع الحرّاس
I see. So the victim was still alive at this point.
فهمت، كانت لا تزال الضحيّة على قيد الحياة حينها
Huh?
ماذا؟
What is it? Something seems different...
ما الأمر؟ هناك شيءٌ مختلف
At 9:10, Chihiro-san leaves.
غادرت تشيهيرو-سان عند 9:10
Then, at 9:20, Yoshioka-san arrives.
بعدها وصل يوشيوكا-سان عند 9:20
But as there's no response, he looks inside...
لكنّه دخل لعدم سماعه ردّاً
...and finds Ms. Ikuko dead.
ووجد جثّة السيّدة إيكوكو
Wait!
!لحظة
Rewind that!
!أعد التسجيل
Right there!
!هنا
Say, why did you go outside?
أخبرني، لمَ خرجت؟
T-To contact the police, of course.
لـ-للاتصال بالشرطة بالطبع
Why would you go outside when there's a phone in here?
لمَ قد تخرج بينما يوجد هاتف هنا؟
That is strange...
ذلك محيّر بالفعل
I was in shock. So I went to my car to get my cell phone.
كـ-كنتُ مصدوماً، لذا ذهبت لسيّارتي لجلب الهاتف الخلوي
You can't blame him; he found a dead body.
ليس مستغرباً، فقد وجد جثّةً أمامه
For someone who ran out shocked,
،بالنسبة لشخص خرج في صدمة
he did spend ten minutes in there.
أمضى 10 دقائق كاملة في الداخل
That's definitely strange.
ذلك غريب بالفعل
What did you do for those ten minutes?
ماذا فعلت في العشر دقائق؟
And look, he's holding something here.
كما انظروا، إنّه يحمل شيئاً
Care to explain, Yoshioka-san?
هلّا شرحت يا يوشيوكا-سان؟
Uhh...
...أنا
Report- Ozawa Detective Agency
تقرير وكالة أوزاوا للتحرّي
I see. So this shows that you embezzled money from the company.
فهمت، يظهر هذا اختلاسك أموالاً من الشركة
I'd be ruined if that were made public!
كنتُ سألقى هلاكي لو خرج الأمر للعلن
So I came to talk with her...
...لذا أتيتُ للكلام معها هنا
But that discussion ended with you killing her!
لكن قادك ذاك الكلام لقتلها
No! She was already dead when I arrived!
!كلا! كانت ميتةً عندما وصلت
Like we can really believe that!
كأنّنا سنصدّق ذلك
It's the truth! But...
...إنّها الحقيقة! لكن
...I thought if this document got out,
...ظننتُني سأكون الأكثر شبهة
I'd be the prime suspect!
!إن اُكتشف الملف
So then you called the police after hiding it in your car?
لذا اتّصلت بالشرطة بعدما أخفيته في سيّارتك؟
That's right!
!أجل
You can give us your excuses down at the station.
أعطنا أعذارك في مركز الشرطة
I didn't do it! She really was dead!
!لم أكن الفاعل! كانت ميتة حقاً
You gotta believe me! I didn't do it!
!صدّقوني! لم أقتلها
What is it? Something isn't right about this body!
ما الأمر؟ هناك ما ليس في محلّه بشأن هذه الجثّة
She was dressed for bed,
كانت ترتدي ثياب نوم
even though she was expecting visitors...
مع أنّها ستستقبل زوّاراً
That's weird.
هذا غريب
What's weird, Ran-neechan?
ما قصدك يا ران-نيتشان؟
Her mouth is wide open, but there aren't any wrinkles at all!
فمها مفتوح بالكامل، لكن لا توجد أيّ تجعّدات
That's it! This was a true death mask!
!فهمت! كان هذا قناع موت حقيقيّ
But Yoshioka-san was supposed to stop by after Chihiro-san, right?
لكنّ يوشيوكا-سان كان سيأتي بعد زيارة تشيهيرو-سان، أليس كذلك؟
And she was strangled to death, right?
كما خُنقت للموت، صحيح؟
Eh? Oh, yeah.
ماذا؟ أ-أجل
It should have wrinkles if she was in pain with it on.
يُفترض أن تكون عليه تجعّدات لو عانت وهي ترتديه
Check it out.
تفقّدوا الأمر
Yes, sir.
حاضر
Which means...
...ما يعني
...the culprit applied the face pack after killing the victim!
!وضع القاتل قناع الوجه بعد قتل الضحيّة
And put her in the bathrobe...
وألبسها ثوب الاستحمام
But what for?!
لكن لمَ؟
She was dressed like this when you were here, right, Chihiro-san?
كانت ترتدي هذا الثوب عندما أتيتِ، صحيح يا تشيهيرو-سان؟
T-That's right.
أ-أجل
W-What?!
ما-ماذا؟
I wasn't the only one!
!لم أكن الوحيدة
The security guards saw her, too!
!رآها الحارسان أيضاً
Y-Yes. When I came over due to a false alarm,
،أ-أجل، عندما أتيتُ بعد الإنذار الخاطئ
Kojima-san was indeed dressed like this.
كانت كوجيما-سان ترتدي هذا الثوب حقّاً
In which case, why would the killer redo her face pack?
في تلك الحالة، لمَ أعاد القاتل وضع قناع الوجه عليها؟
Did anything seem strange?
لم تريا شيئاً غريباً؟
It's hard to say...
...لا أدري تماماً
Are you sure it was her?
أأنتما متأكدتان أنّها كانت هي؟
What about her eyes, ears, or lips, for example?
ماذا عن عينيها وأذنيها، وشفتيها على سبيل المثال؟
Don't be ridiculous.
لا تكن سخيفاً
Her face was covered with the pack and--
...كان القناع يغطي وجهها
Come to think of it,
بالمناسبة
clashed with her white face.
مقابل وجهها الأبيض
She's not wearing lipstick!
!لا ترتدي أحمر شفاه
You mean like Chihiro-san's color?
تقصد كلون تشيهيرو-سان؟
Yes! That was the color!
!أجل! كان ذاك اللون
Aha! So you put the face pack on and met with the guards!
!فهمت! وضعتِ قناع الوجه وقابلتِ الحارسين إذاً
Being turned down for the loan caused you to kill your own mother.
قتلتِ أمّك بيديك لرفضها إقراضك
Your first slip-up was the malfunctioning security alarm.
كانت غلطتك الأولى هو انطلاق الإنذار المعطوب
If there was no response,
،لو لم يكن هناك ردّ
the guards would've entered the house.
كان الحارسان ليدخلا
Surprised, you quickly decided to play the role of your mother.
قررتِ لعب دور أمّك سريعاً عندما فُوجئتِ
With a face pack and a robe, you could fool them.
كان بإمكانك خداعهما بقناع وجه وثوب نوم
You are mother and daughter, after all.
فأنتما أم وابنتها
But in your rush, you met them with your lipstick still on.
لكنك قابلتِهما وأنت تضعين أحمر شفاهك في عجلتك
But you had to remove your mother's lipstick...
لكن كان عليك مسح أحمر شفاه أمّك
Since packs are applied
بما أنّ قناع الوجه
after washing the face and removing makeup.
يُوضع بعد غسل الوجه وإزالة مساحيق التجميل
Yes, I met the guards and put the face pack on my mother!
قابلتُ الحارسين ووضعت !قناع الوجه على أمّي بالفعل
But she was already dead when I got here!
!لكن كانت ميتةً بوقت وصولي
Everyone knows that she and I constantly fought...
يعرف الجميع شجارنا الدائم
I thought everyone would think I killed her, so I...
...ظننتُ أنّي سأقع تحت شبهة قتلها، لذا
You have to believe me! I didn't do it!
!صدّقوني! لم أكن الفاعلة
There's no question that she tried to cover things up.
لا شكّ أنّها حاولت تغطية الأمر
But it doesn't serve as an alibi...
لكن ذلك لا ينفع كحجّة غياب
All it does is change the time of death to be--
...كلّ ما يفعله هو تغيير وقت الوفاة
Change?!
تغيير؟
If the time of death is changed...
...إذا تغيّر وقت الوفاة
What's this?
ما هذا؟
Hey, old man Mori says...
...العمّ موري يقول
What now?
ماذا؟
No, none at all.
كلا، أبداً
That's strange. Why hasn't it turned up?
غريب، لمَ لم يجدوها؟
Could it be?!
!أيمكن؟
Umm, is it okay for me to leave now?
أيمكنني المغادرة الآن؟
Sure. Thanks for your help.
أجل، شكراً على مساعدتك
I'm sure we'll need to talk to you again at some point.
قد نحتاج للكلام معك لاحقاً
Right, I understand!
أجل، أفهم
Conan-kun!
كونان-كن
Sheesh! I told you not to hang around here!
يا إلهي، أخبرتك أن تتوقف عن التجوّل
I-I'm sorry...
آ-آسف
Don't worry about it!
لا تهتم
I knew it!
!كما ظننت
Well, goodbye.
أعتذر منكم إذاً
Alright!
!حسناً
Here we go!
...مُجدداً، مُجدداً
Dad?!
أبي؟
Hold on, Izumi-san.
لا يصحّ هذا يا إيزومي-سان
How can we end this play if the main character leaves the stage?
كيف نسدل الختام على المسرحية إذا غادرت الشخصية الرئيسية؟
W-What do you mean, Mori-san?
ما-ما قصدك يا موري-سان؟
I finally figured out who really killed her.
اكتشفتُ القاتل الحقيقيّ أخيراً
Dad...
...أبي
But you just said that Chihiro-san did it!
لكنّك قلتَ أنّ تشيهيرو-سان هي القاتلة قبل قليل
I said nothing of the sort.
لم أقل ذلك
I merely exposed her cover-up.
كشفتُ حيلتها في تغطية الأمر فحسب
Her unnecessary tampering altered the estimated time of death,
عبثها غير المرغوب عدّل وقت الوفاة المقدّر
which ironically created an alibi for the real killer.
مما صنع حجّة غياب للقاتل الحقيقيّ بشكل ساخر
The real killer?
القاتل الحقيقيّ؟
You don't mean...
...أتقصد
S-Surely you're joking?!
!تـ-تمزح بالتأكيد
You vouched that I was in Beika when the murder took place!
!شهدتَ بأّنّي كنت في بيكا أثناء وقوع الجريمة
But if her testimony is true,
لكن إن ثبتت شهادتُها
then the murder took place before 8:50.
فوقعت الجريمة قبل 8:50
In other words, you could have done it, too.
أي كان بمقدورك تنفيذها
Ridiculous! Are you saying you believe her?!
!سخافة! أتقصد أنّك تصدّقها؟
And what proof do you have that I killed the woman?!
!كما ما الدليل لديك بأنّي قتلتها؟
Chihiro-san. Did your mother have poor eyesight?
تشيهيرو-سان، أكان نظر أمّك ضعيفاً؟
Eh? Y-Yes. But she always wore contacts instead of glasses.
ماذا؟ أ-أجل. لكنّها كانت ترتدي عدسات لاصقة لأنّها تكره النظارات
Please take another look at the victim's body.
هلّا أعدتم تفقّد جثّة الضحيّة
I believe only her left contact is in.
ستجدون عدسة لاصقة في عينها اليسرى فقط
Only the left one is here!
!توجد عدسة لاصقة في اليسرى فحسب
There weren't any contacts in her belongings!
لم تكن هناك عدسات لاصقة في أغراضها
There's no use in looking for it.
لا جدوى من بحثكم
Because the killer has it.
لأنّها بحوزة القاتل
Yes. The missing contact lens is in your pants cuff, Izumi-san!
أجل، العدسة اللاصقة المفقودة !هي في طيّة سروالك يا إيزومي-سان
If you'll excuse me...
...اعذرني
Here it is!
!ها هي
N-No way!
!مـ-مستحيل
That's not a place it could just happen to wind up.
لا يمكن أن تسقط هناك بشكلٍ عابر
It could only happen to someone with direct contact with the victim--
يمكن أن يحصل ذلك فقط ...إذا احتكت الضحيّة بأحدهم
the killer, in other words!
!أي القاتل
She said she was going to sue me for all I had...
قالت أنّها ستقاضيني على كلّ ما أملكه
But I only invested how she told me...
مع أنّي استثمرتُ كما أخبرتني فحسب
But the minute we lost money, she blamed it all on me...
لكن لحظة خسارتنا للمال، ألقت كامل اللوم عليّ
Please! Anything but court! I'll pay it back, however long it--
!أرجوك! أيّ شيء إلّا المحاكم ...سأعيد كلّ مالك مهما طال
I checked the land your parents live on.
تفقّدتُ الأرض التي يعيش عليها والداك
I could postpone things if they sold it...
يمكنني تأجيل المدّة إن باعاها
B-But--!
...لـ-لكن
I already spoke with them.
تكلّمتُ معهما بالفعل
They've agreed to do anything to compensate me.
وافقا على فعل أيّ شيء لتعويضي
Family ties are such a wonderful thing, indeed.
حبّ الأبوين شيء جميل حقّاً
She had to pay... for dragging my elderly parents into this...
لم أستطع مسامحتها... على توريط والديّ في هذا
Good work! You saved the day yet again!
عملٌ موفق، أنقذتنا مجدداً
Oh, I see...
...أ-أجل
The police lost a great man when you left the force!
كانت مغادرتك الشرطة خسارةً كبيرة لنا
Well, see you later!
سنعتمد عليك لاحقاً إذاً
Right!
!أ-أجل
Alright!
!رائع
Ran! Conan! Time to celebrate!
!ران! كونان! وقت الاحتفال
Let's get some food on our way home!
!لنأكل في طريق عودتنا
More ramen, I take it?
المزيد من الرامن فحسب، صحيح؟
Don't be stupid! I'm not talking cheap food here!
!حمقاء! لم أقصد طعاماً رخيصاً
Alright!
!رائع
We'll celebrate with pork ramen!
!سنحتفل برامن اللحم
I figured as much...
...ظننتُ ذلك
That voice!
...ذاك الصوت
Why is Oyama-san sitting formally?
لمَ يجلس أوياما-سان بشكل رسميّ؟
In other words, one of you is the killer!
ما يعني أنّ القاتل بينكم
The blood on the table... And the tablecloth...
...الدماء على الطاولة... وعلى غطائها
Just as the dying message says,
،كما أشارت رسالة الانتحار
the killer is definitely that person!
!القاتل هو ذاك الشخص بلا شكّ
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Snowy Mountain Lodge Murder Case."
جريمة قتل منزل الجبل الثلجي
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Shoji.
شوغي
Next episode we'll fork the rook and check the king!
في الحلقة القادمة، في الجبال الثلجيّة !أمسك بالصخر ومات الشاه
Wait, don't do that yet.
!لا تحرّكها بعد